-==http://www.1000fr.com==- 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
福尔摩斯探案集
The Memoirs Of Sberlock Holmes
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
第七季 第2集 临终的侦探
S7E02
先生 Savage先生
Mr. Savage, sir,
我不知道(您要出门) 先生
I didn't know, sir.
我不知道
Sir, I didn't know.
没关系的 Benson
It's all right, Benson,
临时决定的
last minute decision.
哦 你在这儿啊
Oh, there you are.
早上好 Adelaide
Adelaide, good morning.
Victor去哪啦?
Where has Victor gone?
Victor?
Victor
Victor.
不要装作你不知道
Please don't pretend you are ignorant of where he is.
我是我表弟的监护人么?
Am I my cousin's keeper?
要是你告诉我他去哪了 我会很感激你的
I shall be obliged that you would tell me where he has gone.
我知道他要去干什么
I know what he's gone to do.
但他去了哪里呢?
Where has he gone?
你应该比我更容易知道这一点吧 亲爱的
You have the advantage of me, my dear.
我还想着今早和他 去看看家里的农场呢
I was expecting to walk over to home farm with him this morning.
你就一点不同情我们么?
Have you no pity for us?
是你怂恿他过这种噩梦似的生活
You encouraged him into this nightmarish life.
我"同情"你
I pity for you
和你可爱的孩子们
at Somerleigh House
在Somerleigh庄园
with your lovely children,
你们彼此之间相亲相爱
the love you have for each other.
他到底去哪里了?
Where has he gone?
看得出我不受欢迎
I can see I am unwelcome,
恐怕只是因为些不经意的错误
some unwitting fault I fear.
我应该回城里去
I shall return to town
好给你留个清净
and leave you in peace.
-Hudson太太 -华生医生
-Oh, Mrs. Hudson. -Oh, Dr. Watson.
我们都很想你
We have been missing you.
噢 是么 才10天没见
Oh yeah, only another 10 days.
是啊
Yes.
早上好 福尔摩斯
Morning, Holmes.
别要我评论你的新领带
Don't ask me to comment on your new tie.
真够无情的 福尔摩斯
Quite heartless, Holmes.
那个女人无疑是想到这来
That woman is undoubtedly coming here.
她一直盯著这扇窗户
She's been staring up at this window
已经有三分钟了
for the past three minutes.
我真希望她能下定决心
Oh, I do wish she'd make up her mind.
我会让Hudson太太给她多加只杯子的
I could ask Mrs. Hudson to bring up an extra cup.
很漂亮 不是么?
Handsome, isn't she?
谁?
Who?
一定是什么重要的事
It must be something of importance
才让她犹豫了这么久
to make her hesitate so long,
一个委托人?
A client?
还好么 Polly?
Alright, Polly?
真是个可人儿
There's a good girl.
Savage先生 我是John Gedgrave
Mr. Savage, John Gedgrave.
你怎么才来啊?
Where the devil have you been?
先生 先预付2镑
Two pounds, Mr. Savage, in advance
事成之后再付3镑
and three for the establishment,
一共是5英镑
five in total.
希望能值这个价
Hope it's worth it.
您用的匿名
Oh, anonymous was the word you used.
我们去的这地方
Where we're going is as anonymous
也不可能被人发现的
as you'll ever find.
每个小隔间
Every compartment
都还有帘子挡著
has a curtain even.
没人会看到您的
No one will see you,
哦 上帝啊
oh good Lord,
您没都带着吧 是不是?
you're not taking these with you, are you?
不用带着?
No?
哦 不 当然不用
Oh, no, no, no, no.
或许应该把它们撕碎了
May as well tear them up
扔到泰晤士河里
and drop them in the Thames.
四十镑
Forty pounds,
我会给您开张收据的
I'll give you a receipt.
福尔摩斯!
Holmes!
应该是我们漂亮的客人
That will be our fair visitor.
请坐吧
Please, do sit down.
Gedgrave 这张收据
This receipt Gedgrave.
怎么啦?
What about it?
你在玩什么把戏?
What are you playing at?
签的名是Carter
You signed it Carter.
您不会是希望我在做这类事情的时候
You don't expect me to use my real name
还要用我的真名吧?
doing this sort of work, do you?
Carter就是我的真名
Carter's my real name.
我本来可以随便写个名字
I could have signed anything
我信任您才用真名的 Savage先生
but I entrusted you with my real name, Mr. Savage.
您就别再抱怨了
Please don't complain.
我需要您的帮助
I need your help.
我是...
I am...
您在这里所说的一切
Anything you say here will of course
我们都会严格的保守秘密
be treated in the strictest confidence.
我们还替国王们保守着秘密呢 夫人
We have kept the secrets of kings, madam.
我...
I...
我丈夫...
My husband...
我丈夫是个金融家
My husband is a financier.
您一定听过牛津伦巴德银行吧?
You have heard of the Oxford and Lombard Bank?
是的
Yes.
Conyers家族是其主要股东
The chief shareholders are the Conyers?
我丈夫的母亲就属于这一家族
My husband's family on his mother's side.
我丈夫是主要董事之一
He is one of the directors.
他完全胜任这个工作
The job is well within his powers, only...
但他发现这工作越来越令人厌烦
Victor has found the work increasingly irksome.
他怀抱着一种志向
He entertains an ambition, you see,
虽然家里人都无法理解
which none of his family would begin to understand.
什么志向?
What is that?
他想成为一个诗人
He wishes to be a poet.
他开始相信
He's come to believe
吸食鸦片能获得灵感
that opium heightens his powers,
让他的感觉更敏锐
intensifies the evidence of his senses.
这可能能起到临时的作用
This may be so temporarily,
但我想您肯定知道
but as I'm sure you know
只有在最开始几次吸食时
the effect only survives
才有这种效果
the first few times the drug is taken.
是这样么?
That is so, is it not?
是的 完全正确
Oh, yes, indeed.
接下来很快就会上瘾
Addiction quickly follows,
越来越频繁
very often for life.
这种恶魔般的物质 很快就只会使人沉醉其中
The infernal substance soon offers the addict nothing
除了在无法吸食时 感到难以忍受以外别无他用
except relief from the terrible effects of its absence.
我相信Victor马上就要成瘾了
I believe Victor stands on the threshold of addiction.
他今早留给我一张便条
He left a note for me this morning
似乎他明白自己处在何种危险之中
which suggests he knows what danger he's in.
您要走了么?
You are going?
很清楚 在这件事情上 华生医生才是您应该去咨询的人
Well clearly Dr. Watson is the person to consult for the matter.
不 福尔摩斯先生 不是的
No, Mr. Holmes, no,
不光是这些
there is much more to it then that.
有一位Culverton Smith先生
There is Mr. Culverton Smith.
Culverton Smith?
Victor的表兄
Victor's cousin.
他肯定是起了什么坏的影响
He's a malign influence.
是他把Victor逼到这份上的
I am sure he's driven Victor to this
我确信他这么做另有目的
and I am certain he's done it for his own ends.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
马车就停在街角
The cab's on the corner.
我希望这次不是白费力气
I do hope this is not a wild goose chase.
怎么可能呢?
How can it be?
好吧
Well,
我想那个漂亮姑娘把你 迷的晕头转向 谢谢
I think you've had your head turned by a pretty woman, thank you.
对了 关于Culverton Smith 有什么情况?
Oh yes, what about Culverton Smith?
我调查过他了
I looked him up.
Culverton Smith在东方的时候
Culverton Smith did some important medical work
从事过重要的医学工作
while he was in the east.
他拓宽了科学的领域
He pushed back the boundaries of science.
但是 他却不得不自费发表他的发现
However, he was obliged to publish his findingsat his own expense.
为什么?
Why?
他只是个业余爱好者
He's an amateur
那些专家们又很嫉妒
and the professionals are jealous.
我明白为什么他使你感兴趣了
Well I can see why he interests you.
你那些神秘的客人
Ah, your mystery guests.
他们都是谁?
Who are they?
我可不愿意让Carnac上校 成为唯一的名人
I couldn't let Colonel Carnac be the only celebrity.
我不是因为他有名才请他的 亲爱的
I don't want him at our table because he's a celebrity, my darling.
纯粹是因为他有钱
It's just that he's horribly rich,
或者说他妻子非常有钱
or rather his wife is,
他们都把钱存在牛津伦巴德银行
and they bank with the Oxford and Lombard.
我个人觉得没有比 在餐桌上猎取奇闻异事更糟的了
Personally I can't think of anything worse then hunting stories all through dinner.
我也这么觉得
Nor I.
所以我说服一位很有趣的猎人 也来加入我们
So I've persuaded a rather more interesting hunter to join us.
是谁? 不要捉弄我 Addy
Who is it? Don't tease, Addy.
歇洛克 福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
要我说 这可真是出乎意料
I say, that is something of a coup,
好极了
well done.
看 Culverton Smith也来了
Oh look, Culverton Smith's here too.
真高兴你又能邀请他 Addy 我亲爱的
I'm so glad you felt able to invite him again, Addy darling.
看看他
Look at him.
大家都会觉得Somerleigh是他的
Anyone would think Somerleigh was his.
我很不喜欢这样
I do dislike it.
-歇洛克 福尔摩斯先生? -是的
-Mr. Sherlock Holmes? -Yes.
我是Culverton Smith
Culverton Smith.
Adelaide告诉我有一位 令人惊喜的客人
Dear Adelaide promised me a surprise guest.
我还担心是因为哗众取宠而出名的人呢
I feared it might be somebody who was famous for being famous.
我没有料到 是您这种级别的
Someone of your distinction I had not expected at all.
我当然没有你出名
Nor I one of yours.
我?
Mine?
我没权要求这种待遇 福尔摩斯先生
I make no claims to distinction, Mr. Holmes.
您过谦了
You are too modest.
你写的关于苏门答腊和洪水热的 病理学报告是一部杰作
Your account of the pathology of the Sumatra and River Fever is a masterpiece.
谢谢
Thank you,
thank you.
当然 要让诱饵发挥作用
For a lure to work, of course,
得让动物相信这是安全的
you have to make the animal believe it's safe.
这样就好了
Now that's all very well.
但是 动物们对于危险总是很敏感
The animals involved, however, have a highly developed sense of danger.
我想福尔摩斯先生对危险也很敏感 是吗 福尔摩斯先生?
I'm sure Mr. Holmes must have that sense, do you Mr. Holmes?
是的 我看得出来
Yes, I see it.
那么 你是说侦探
Yes, you mean that the detective
可以说是在
could be said to move
食肉动物和牺牲品的世界里活动
in a world of predators and victims.
我们都是这样的 上校
Oh, we all do that Colonel.
即使是最不起眼的家庭事务律师
Even humble family solicitors.
是的 那你给自己树了不少敌吧 福尔摩斯先生
Yes, and you would have enemies, Mr. Holmes,
你就没有敌人么?
would you not?
对了 我敢说要是
Yes, yes, it would take something I dare say
有人想引福尔摩斯先生上钩然后对付他
to bring Mr. Holmes onto a lure
肯定要花很多工夫
and dispatch him.
需要仔细研究他的习惯
It would take careful study of his habits
在暗处发动袭击
and half-light shot or worse.
必要时甚至要跟踪他
It might even be necessary to follow him
一直追到他的老窝里去
up to his lair even.
Bertram 安静点
Bertram, be quiet.
您没有怎么吃东西 福尔摩斯先生
You're not eating, Mr. Holmes.
有这么多东西要观察
With so much to observe,
吃就是次要的了
food becomes of secondary importance.
您都观察出了些什么?
What have you observed so far?
勇气
Courage,
燥热
fever,
贪婪
gluttony,
愤怒
acute irritation,
嫉妒
envy,
机智
wit, intelligence,
我是说都是些在英格兰所有大庄园里
I mean just the usual vices and virtues
常见的恶性和美德
with any large English country house.
真是好极了
This is very good.
你们知道
Do you know the game
"推硬币"的游戏么?
of "shove ha'penny?"
这个跟那个很像
Well it's similar.
我把它叫做"地毯滑冰"
I call this one "Rug skatery".
我那些把赌博当一回事的朋友
My more serious gambling friends,
就是那些股票经纪人
the stock broking fraternity that is to say,
因为把这游戏介绍到自己的居所
have introduced it to their establishments
而惹得妻子们非常生气
to the fury of their wives.
但是大家都同意
It is agreed, however,
论其可靠性来 Somerleigh是最好的
that the authentic Somerleigh version is best.
她压根儿不穿那些东西
And she never wore them at all.
要是我们不鼓动他们去玩那个愚蠢的游戏 男人们会感到苦恼么?
Will the men be mortified if we don't cheer them on at their silly game?
我敢说他们会的
I dare say they will.
这都快成个反面的理由了
It's almost a reason for not doing it.
还不是为了和睦
But for the sake of harmony
我们才迁就这些大孩子
We indulge little boys.
主人又一次超过了大家的预测
Our host has again out jumped all estimates.
-所以律师压对了 -谢谢
-So the lawyer takes the pot. -Thank you.
干得好 Charles
Well done, Charles,
现在该我了
my turn now.
先生们 咱们来赌一把吧
Faites vos jeux, gentlemen
我该把你们最后一次的预测减半
I should halve your estimates of last time.
-妈妈 -没事的
-Mama. -It's quite all right.
我家的孩子也一样
My children do that too.
妈妈
Mama.
爸爸他怎么啦?
What is wrong with papa?
他抱着我的时候
When he hugged me
我觉得很恐怖
he felt horrid.
他浑身冰冷 还在发抖
He felt all cold and shivery.
你想说什么 宝贝?
What do you mean by that, darling?
好像他就快要死了
He felt as if he was dead.
别说傻话了
Oh don't be silly.
医生!
Doctor!
Smith
Smith.
可怜的家伙
Poor fellow.
我没能帮到他 福尔摩斯先生
I could do nothing for him, Mr. Holmes,
连我也没帮得到他
not even I.
护士也在尽力照顾
The nursing was all right, too,
真是一出悲剧
a tragic business.
有一件事 您能帮助我么?
Will you satisfy me upon one point?
当然
Of course.
对这种疾病 您知道多少?
This disease, do you know what it was?
所有症状都显示这是一种热病
All the signs point to that class of fevers,
其中苏门答腊洪水热是最致命的
of which the Sumatran River Fever is the most deadly.
但并不一定就是这种病
It was not necessarily that however.
那也非常接近
Something very like it.
我已经建议这个可怜人的尸体
I have advised that the poor fellow's body
必须格外小心地来处理
is handled with extreme care.
这种疾病是通过皮肤 表面的创口来传播的
It is a disease transmitted through broken skin you see.
他们必须最最小心
They cannot be too careful.
Savage怎么会染上这种病?
How did Savage come by such a thing?
噢 您可以对此保持谨慎的态度么?
Ah, I can rely on your discretion?
当然
Of course.
我知道他有时 经常呃
I understand Savage sometimes frequented,
或者这么说 有些事使他必须去
well let's to say his affairs took him
Rotherhithe的某个地方
to a part in Rotherhithe
那里主要住的都是中国和印度的水手
inhabited mostly by Chinese and Lascars.
他肯定是在那里染上这种病的
He must have picked it up there.
应该通知Rotherhithe官方这件事
The authorities in Rotherhithe must be informed.
他们会知道的
They will be.
但他们会不会采取适当措施
Whether the measures they take
那就另当别论了
turn out to be appropriate is another matter.
恐怕在大多数机构中的懒惰
Most institutions I'm afraid
都可以够得上判刑了
are run by the criminally lazy.
我认识Penrose Fisher和几个主管
I know Penrose Fisher and the director a little,
我会尽我所能去做的
I'll do what I can.
很感激您的关心 福尔摩斯先生
I'm grateful for you interest, Mr. Holmes.
可怜的Adelaide
Poor Adelaide,
这打击太沉重了
this will hit her very hard.
(寄生虫热病病理)
PATHOLOGY OF PABASITIC FEVERS
(金融家英年早逝--热病死亡之谜)
UNTIMELY DEATH OF FINANCIER
离开Somerleigh?
Leave Somerleigh?
我必须离开Somerleigh么?
I must leave Somerleigh?
一旦遗嘱被确认
As soon as will is proved,
Culverton Smith就有权要求你离开
Culverton Smith is within his rights to ask you to go.
我很抱歉 Adelaide
I'm very sorry, Adelaide.
所有这些都是按照Bernard爵士的遗嘱
All this has its origins in Sir Bernard's will.
我也有部分责任
And partly I blame myself.
继承人限于Victor最年长的表兄
This entailment to Victor's oldest cousin of the house
继承房屋和其余的...
and the rest of it is...
其余的什么?
The rest of it?
从伯克郡产业取得的收入
The income from the Berkshire estate.
那也要归他么?
That will go to him, too?
是的
Yes.
天啊 那还能剩下什么?
Dear God, what is left?
足够你个人
Enough for you to live,
适度而体面的生活
modestly and respectably.
当然 现在这种生活不能继续了
You will not be able to continue as you have done.
我明白了
No, I see.
要我说 我曾经多次要Victor修改
As I say, I had asked Victor many times
遗嘱里限定继承人的范围
to change the terms of the entail
这样可以让你舒服地过一辈子
to favor you in your lifetime.
同时也是完全合法的
It would have been legal of course,
这很容易做 但...
easily done but,
Victor太年轻了
Victor was young.
当然 Culverton Smith
Surely, Culverton Smith
不会行使他的权利去驱逐Savage夫人吧
will not exercise his right to evict Mrs. Savage?
他会的
He might.
为什么你这么想?
Why do you think that?
他一直在接触这件事
He's been in touch.
似乎也知道主要的遗产如何处理
He seems to know the main dispositions of the will.
他说过对产业的收入
He talked of the estate income
要进行恰当的使用
being put to a proper use,
不知道具体是指什么
whatever that meant.
他似乎认为Adelaide
He seemed to think that Adelaide
可以去依靠她的娘家
would be able to rely on her family.
他们也没有办法
They have no means.
当他知道了他就会宽容的
When he knows that he must relent.
我很怀疑
I doubt it.
自从进入我们的生活
He's wanted something like this to happen
他就处心积虑要这样
ever since he came into our lives.
他总是利用Victor的弱点
He encouraged all that was weakest in Victor
希望发生什么不幸
in the hope of some disaster.
他现在得偿所愿了
This is a triumph for him.
或许值得和他谈谈 Adelaide
It may be worth talking to him, Adelaide.
我也觉得是
I suppose so.
如果你肯亲自去求他
If you could bring yourself to plead with him.
为了孩子 我会那么做的
For the children I will do even that.
Percy 快擦擦鼻子
Oh, Percy, do blow your nose.
现在记住这些都发生在9天前
Now remember all this happened nine days ago.
那一天是
That was the day when
女王招待苏丹的Kallipur
the Queen entertained the Sultan of Kallipur
也是Frivolous赢得Birkenhead奖金的那一天
and Frivolous won the Birkenhead Stakes.
-是在Goodwood赢的 -没错
-At Goodwood. -Right.
Harry 你的靴子呢?
Harry, where are your boots?
我知道了
Oh I see.
那就快去Rotherhithe吧
Well then off to Rotherhithe.
祝你们好运
Good luck,
good luck.
这个 福尔摩斯
There Holmes,
是一份在皮肤表面找到的
that is a list of every blemish
全部斑点的清单
I could find on the skin's surface.
我猜你要寻找传播途径吧
I presume you're seeking the means of transmission?
是的
Yes.
通过皮肤表面的创口
Through broken skin.
Culverton Smith也认为是这么传播的
That is how Culverton Smith believes it was transmitted.
他的意见当然值得参考
Well his opinion is worth knowing certainly.
Fisher 你觉得这个人怎么样?
What do you think of him, Fisher?
他是你朋友么?
He is a friend of yours?
当然不 我并不了解他
Not at all, I hardly know him.
只是读了他的一些论文 仅此而已
I have read a couple of his papers, that's all.
我认为他的工作
Well I think his work,
至少有些部分是很杰出的
in parts, brilliant.
要说有什么缺点的话
If he has a fault it is
那就是不能接受任何的批评
that he can accept no criticism whatsoever.
我确实发现了一个昆虫叮咬点
I did find an insect bite
但皮肤上再没有其他叮咬的痕迹了
but no other punctures of skin at all.
我甚至检查了他的口腔
I even looked inside the mouth.
显然没有任何人为的迹象
It seems clear that no human agency was involved.
我猜你是在调查
I assume you're investigating
这种疾病被什么人
the possibility of this disease
蓄意传播的可能性
having been passed on deliberately.
和你这样思维严密的人会面
Well what a unique delight
真是格外令人愉快
to meet a man with a mind as logical as yours?
是他么?
Is this him?
是的 福尔摩斯先生?
Uh, yes, Mr. Holmes?
噢 好小子
Ah, bravo Ben.
你是?
You are?
Gedgrave
Gedgrave,
John Gedgrave
John Gedgrave.
我是福尔摩斯
Holmes.
这边走
This way.
我一看到报纸就认出是他了
Recognized him as soon as I seen the newspaper.
肯定是他
That's him all right.
你具体都为他干些什么?
How did you come to be acting for him?
广告 慎重的绅士需要
Advert, gentleman of discretion required
码头礼仪的知识
with knowledge of dock etiquette.
码头礼仪?
Dock etiquette?
为了知道烟馆附近的路
For knowing your way around the poppy houses, opium.
烟馆 我知道一两个不错的地方
Well I knew one or two of the better places.
是Savage登的广告么?
Was the advertisement placed by Savage?
不是
No.
那是谁?
Who then?
我不知道
I don't know.
Gedgrave先生 你不会对我撒谎吧
Mr. Gedgrave, you wouldn't lie to me would you?
不 绝不会
Oh no.
我是在租来的办公室里见到那个家伙的
It was some fellow I met in a rented office.
给我描述一下他
Describe him for me?
我做不到
Well I can't.
这么说是什么意思
Well what I mean is,
我从来没见过这家伙
I never saw the fellow.
他故意不让我看到
He didn't mean me to.
他一直拿灯在我眼前闪来闪去
He kept a light shining in my eyes all the time.
真的是这样 这是在什么时候?
Indeed. When was this?
14号
The 14th.
他付钱
He paid all right.
要我去和他联系
He told me I was to be contacted and I was,
我就去见他了
to meet him.
他怎么了
What happened to him?
我可不想惹上什么麻烦
I don't want any trouble.
为这我才来找你的
That's why I come to you.
你把他带到哪去了?
Where did you take him?
公爵巷的一间房子
A house in Duke's Alley.
那可是个好地方
It's a good place.
好?
Good?
从来没出过什么问题 真是个好地方
Well, never had any problems there, good place.
他到底怎么了?
What happened to him?
福尔摩斯!
Holmes!
对不起我没想...
I'm sorry I didn't...
谢谢你 Gedgrave先生 给你添麻烦了
Thank you, Mr. Gedgrave, for your trouble.
随时恭候 福尔摩斯先生 随时
Anytime, Mr. Holmes, anytime.
您真慷慨 先生
Generous of you, sir, generous.
我需要一个Rotherhithe的向导
I will need a guide in Rotherhithe.
要是你要去那的话 您可是找对人了
If you want the best places, I'm your man.
不用找别人了
Look no further.
明天早上
Tomorrow morning,
十点半怎么样?
10:30?
好的
Done.
您去红拖鞋俱乐部
The Red Slipper Club.
找叫Carter的
Ask for Carter,
Frank Carter
Frank Carter.
就是你吧 Gedgrave先生
Will that be you, Mr. Gedgrave?
Hudson太太
Mrs. Hudson,
华生医生可能会留下来吃晚饭
Dr. Watson may be staying for dinner.
华生
Now Watson.
Culverton Smith要把
Culverton Smith means to
Savage夫人和她的孩子
throw Mrs. Savage and her children
都从Somerleigh庄园赶出去
out of Somerleigh House.
他凭什么那么做?
How is he able to do that?
根据一个没有修改的老遗嘱
The house is entailed to him an old will,
庄园限定由他来继承
which has never been revised.
那就有趣了
Well that is interesting.
你知道这意味着什么?
You know what this means?
意味着Culverton Smith
It means that Culverton Smith had a motive
有了除掉他表弟的动机
for doing away with his cousin.
Savage死了
Savage is dead,
死于一种疾病 偏偏Culverton Smith
killed by a disease in which Culverton Smith
是研究该疾病公认的专家
was the acknowledged expert.
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no.
你是故意装作没有理解我吧?
Are you deliberately trying to misunderstand me?
你只不过是指出了一个 值得注意的巧合
You have pointed out a remarkable coincidence,
仅此而已
that is all.
不能做出任何的推论
No inferences can be drawn from it.
我们不能容许Savage夫人
We cannot allow Mrs. Savage
被那家伙扫地出门
to be thrown into the street by this fellow.
我们也无能为力
We may have to.
租办公室的人一定就是Culverton Smith
It must have been Culverton Smith who rented the office.
可这证明不了什么
I dare say but it proves nothing.
肯定有办法阻止他的 福尔摩斯 肯定有
There must be a way of stopping him, Holmes, surely.
我越来越怀疑这一点了
Oh, I doubt it more and more.
如果你认为他有罪
Suppose you were convinced of his guilt.
你会怎么做呢?
What would you do then?
你知道我的方法的
You know my methods,
我会想办法进到庄园里去
I would gain entry to the house.
我该这么去做
Then that's what I shall do.
你不一定非得来的
You don't have to come.
然而我还是得来
Nevertheless, I shall.
你的脑袋已经转过去了
You already had your head turned.
我得保证 你的脖子不会跟着折断
I must make sure you don't get your neck broken as well.
当可怜的Savage相信
Once poor Savage had been convinced
鸦片会为他打开
that opium would open the door
诗歌艺术的神秘大门
to the mysteries of the poetic craft,
他就落入了Culverton Smith的股掌中 是吧?
Culverton Smith would have had him in his power, wouldn't he?
他有意识地利用Savage的负罪感
He traded on Savage's sense of guilt.
他知道
He knew that Savage
Savage会在远离Somerleigh的地方
would want to continue experimenting with the drug
继续吸食鸦片
far away from Somerleigh.
华生 你必须要知道
What you have to face, Watson,
表面看来Savage是在Rotherhithe
is that Savage's catching the disease in Rotherhithe
染上这种病的
is entirely plausible,
巧的是
The coincidence,
Smith是这种病方面的专家
that Smith's expertise in the matter is exactly that,
一个巧合
a coincidence.
你不能凭这么个巧合就判他绞刑
You can't hang a man on coincidence.
夫人
Ma'am,
ma'am.
我们有理由相信
We have reason to believe that,
事实上
well as a matter of fact
您侵入了私人领地
you are trespassing.
警官
Sergeant,
我相信你我都清楚
I'm sure you're as aware as I am
这个国家关于侵入私人领地的法律
the laws of trespass in this country
是最古怪 甚至离谱的
are most curious not to say odd.
我应该知道
I should know.
数百英亩的土地
I have responsibility for hundreds of acres
从我手里被人以貌似合法的手段骗走
which are about to be stolen from me
我有责任
through legal trickery,
就是那个人骗走了土地
by that man,
这个人像寄生虫一样
a man who preyed on my husband
掠夺着我的丈夫
like some bloated parasite,
腐蚀他 把他推向死亡
corrupted him and drove him to his death.
而现在
And now,
他却不和那个可怜的寡妇
now he will not speak to the woman
说一句话
he has widowed.
他当然不会的
Of course he won't,
他知道他这一边根本就没有正义
he knows he has no justice on his side.
只有冷血的形式合法
Merely cold legality.
Benson
Benson,
Savage夫人应该回到庄园
Mrs. Savage should now return to Somerleigh House.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
夫人 我向你保证
Ma'am, you have my assurance,
我会追着Culverton Smith不放的
I will pursue Culverton Smith.
我是不会停止的
I will not rest
除非他宣布放弃这个要毁灭你的计划
until he's renounced his plans to ruin you.
福尔摩斯先生呢?
And Mr Holmes?
我明白了
I see.
我不怪他
I do not blame him.
他只不过是和其他人看法一样
He only sees it as the world sees it,
看到了不幸
unfortunate and cold hearted
或许还有Smith先生的冷心肠
on Mr. Smith's part perhaps.
但却不能给谁加罪
But no case to answer,
不能给谁加罪
no case to answer.
Smith!
这仅仅是一个巧合么
It is a singular coincidence, is it not,
你能因一个人的死而继承这么多财产
that you should inherit so much
这个人偏偏死于
from a man who dies of a disease
你最有研究的那种疾病
upon which you are the sole expert.
为什么!
Why!
仅仅归结为巧合是不能令人信服的
Coincidence, bordering upon the unbelievable.
我来告诉你
Let me tell you
过去向你关闭的
the doors of your profession,
专业研究的大门
which had been closed to you,
现在将对你永远的锁上
will now be locked
永远的锁上
and bolted against you.
而这就是我的使命
It is my mission.
这里
Yes.
您的信件 福尔摩斯先生
The post, Mr. Holmes.
罗得西亚(在非洲)烟草
Rhodesian tobacco,
Jeremiah Carlisle寄
Jeremiah Carlisle.
Savage夫人
Mrs. Savage,
我知道您有足够的理智
I know you'll be sensible enough
不需要依赖这些东西
not to come to rely on this
但这还是有助于您度过这段困难时期
but it will help you through these difficult days.
谢谢您 医生
Thank you doctor.
医生 你得赶快来  福尔摩斯先生不行了
Doctor, you must come quickly, it's Mr. Holmes.
-福尔摩斯? -是的
-Mr. Holmes? -Yes.
为什么不早一点来叫我?
Why didn't you call me sooner?
他不让我来
He wouldn't give me leave.
我说不管同不同意 我都要请医生
So I said permission or no, I am.
他才说 那就叫华生来吧
And he said well let it be Watson then.
我怕他快不行了
I think he's dying.
Hudson太太
Now, now, Mrs. Hudson.
肯定没有您说的那么糟糕
I'm sure it's not as bad as you fear.
可他不让我靠近他
But he won't let me near him.
他一点东西都没有吃
He hasn't eaten a scrap.
他喝了很多水吧?
He has had plenty to drink, right?
三天了 他滴水未进
Not a drop has past his lips these three days
他去过Rotherhithe
and he's been to Rotherhithe.
他觉得就是在那传染上了热病
He thinks he caught the fever there.
-天哪 -他要死了 医生
-Good God. -He's dying doctor.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
华生 我们是陷入困难时期了
Watson, we have fallen upon bad times.
我亲爱的伙伴
My dear fellow...
退后 请你往后退!
Stand back, please stand right back!
不然我就把你赶出去
I'll have you thrown out of the house.
我想帮助你
I wish to help.
要真想帮助我 就照我说的做
The best thing you can do to help is to do what you're told.
当然
Of course.
关于Culverton Smith 是我们弄错了
We were wrong about Culverton Smith.
或许我不喜欢他
Maybe I don't like the man
但他不是谋杀犯
but he's no murderer.
洪水热在Rotherhithe蔓延
The River Fever is abroad in Rotherhithe.
福尔摩斯 我们得立刻送你上医院
Holmes, we must get you to a hospital at once.
不 和我保持距离
No, Now keep your distance!
你不知道这病是会传染的么
Don't you see this thing is contagious?
你觉得我会在意这个么?
Do you think such a consideration weighs with me?
离我远点!
Keep your distance!
这病可能会传遍整个伦敦
This could run through London.
是痉挛
It's cramps.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
非要请医生的话
If I had a doctor at least
至少得请个让我信得过的
let me have someone whom I have confidence?
你信不过我?
You have none in me?
你的友情 当然信得过
Your friendship, yes.
可你只是一名普通的执业医师
But you're only a general practitioner
经验不足
with mediocre qualifications.
你的这评论可不足取 福尔摩斯
That remark is unworthy of you, Holmes.
它清楚地向我表明了 你神经焦躁不安的状态
It shows me very clearly the state of your nerves.
它证明了你的无知
That demonstrates your ignorance.
你对塔帕努里(印尼地名)热病 知道多少?
What do you know about Tapanuli Fever?
你知道福摩萨(葡萄牙人对台湾的称呼) 黑色败血症么?
What do you know about Black Formosa corruption?
我从来没有听过这两种病
I have never heard of either.
这是东方奇怪的病症
That is strange pathological disorders in the east.
要是你信不过我 我去请Jasper Meek
If you have no faith in me, let me fetch Jasper Meek.
还有Penrose Fisher 另外Ainstree也在伦敦
Penrose Fisher, Ainstree is here in London.
我去把他找来
Let me fetch him.
只有一个人能帮助我
There's only one man who can help me.
一个被我们中伤过的人
It's a man we have maligned.
Culverton Smith? 你相信他会帮忙么?
Culverton Smith? Do you believe he would help?
他必须帮
He must.
这是我唯一的机会了
It is my only chance.
牡蛎
Oysters,
它们真的会繁殖 不是么?
they do breed don't they?
我不能想象整个海底
I cannot think that the whole bottom of the ocean
就是一团硬硬的牡蛎
is one solid mass of oysters.
福尔摩斯 你能听见我说话么?
Holmes, can you hear me?
我马上就出门去找Culverton Smith
I'm going for Culverton Smith this instant.
那你去吧
Then go.
我会把他带回来的
I'm to bring him back here with me.
他是研究洪水热的专家
He's the emperor of river fevers,
你要说服他来这里
of course you must persuade him
但你得找个借口先回来
but you must return alone.
随便什么借口 别跟他一起回来
Any excuse not to come with him.
跟他说我很抱歉 真的很抱歉
Tell him I apologize, I do.
别让我失望 华生
Don't fail me Watson.
当然不会的
Of course not.
那些河流里
And what of rivers.
没有天敌
Are there no natural enemies
来限制那些生物的繁殖么?
to limit the increase of these creatures?
可怕
It's horrible,
太可怕了
horrible.
我要见Culverton Smith 这事很重要
It's essential that I see Mr. Culverton Smith.
先生 Culverton Smith先生
Mr. Culverton Smith, sir,
不希望在他工作时
does not appreciate being disturbed
有人打扰
during his hours of study.
-等一下 您不能... -Smith!
-Just a minute sir, you can't just... -Smith!
先生
Sir!
Smith!
别这样 先生!
Please sir!
Smith!
先生 您不能这样
Sir, you can't just,
您不能进去 先生
you can't just walk in, sir.
噢 Smith
Ah, Smith.
您这么做是要干什么 先生?
What the devil do you mean by this, sir?
我是为了歇洛克 福尔摩斯来的
I've come from Sherlock Holmes.
他病的很重
He is desperately ill,
他请求您去看看他
and he begs you to come to him.
为什么?
Why?
您就是个医生 可以照顾他
You are a physician, tend to him yourself.
他相信你是唯一能救他的人
He believes that you are the only man who can save him.
救他?
Save him?
我求你来看看吧
I beg you to come.
他感染了什么病了?
What has he contracted?
他想就是害死你表弟的那种热病
He thinks it is the fever which killed your cousin.
他怎么能染上那种病?
How did he come by it?
他去过Rotherhithe
He has been in Rotherhithe.
噢
Ah,
真令人遗憾
I'm sorry to hear this.
我希望您弄错了
I hope you are wrong.
尽管那天他侮辱了我
Despite his insulting behavior the other day,
我仍旧尊重他的才智
I have every respect for his talents.
他的业余爱好是研究犯罪
He's an amateur of crime
就像我的业余爱好是研究疾病
as I am of disease.
坏人之于他
For him the villain,
仿佛细菌之于我
for me the microbe.
这里是我的囚徒
Here are my prisoners.
在这些培养基的明胶里
Among these gelatin cultivations,
有世界上最凶恶的犯人在服刑
some of the worst offenders in the world are doing time.
求你了 已经没有时间可以浪费了
Please, please, there is no time to lose.
他都病得快死了
He is desperately ill.
这跟我有什么相干?
Of what consequence is that to me?
他用最无礼的态度对我造谣中伤
He maligned me in the most outrageous manner.
他为此感到后悔 他一直在重复这一点
He, he regrets it, he was most  insistent upon that point.
他知道热病在Rotherhithe流行
He knows that the fever was abroad in Rotherhithe.
他病了有多久了?
How long has he been ill?
三天了
Three days.
他有没有神智昏迷 胡言乱语?
Is he delirious?
有时候很严重
Sometimes seriously so.
我立刻随你一起去
I will come with you at once.
我另外还约了点事情 先生
I have another appointment, sir.
那好 我就自己去
Very well, I shall go alone.
最多半个小时 我就会到
Staples, you can rely on my being there in a half an hour at most.
你见到他了么?
Did you see him?
是的 他正在赶来
Yes, he's coming.
你是最好的信使
Ah, you're the best of messengers.
你可以离开这里了
You can disappear from the scene now.
我应该留下来听听他的意见 福尔摩斯
I should stay to hear his opinion, Holmes,
真的很有必要
I really should.
他敏感的近乎病态
No reason he is morbidly sensitive.
我们必须让他独自展现他的技艺
We must let him practice his arts alone.
-亲爱的福尔摩斯 -前门有动静
-My dear, Holmes. -That's the front door,
是他
It's him.
快藏起来
Hide.
藏起来
快 如果你爱我的话
Quick, if you love me.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
哦 Smith 我不敢奢望你能来
Oh, Smith, I hardly dared to hope.
我也想不到
I should imagine not.
看 我还是来了
Yet you see I'm here.
要以德报怨 福尔摩斯
Coals of fire Holmes,
以德报怨 (coals of fire典出圣经 撒下22:13)
coals of fire.
真是高尚
It's noble.
你知道你得了什么病么?
Do you know what is wrong with you?
是的
Yes.
你知道这些症状么?
You recognize the symptoms?
是的 很清楚
Yes, quite well.
那你是病了三天了?
Three days with you then?
是的
Yes.
你坚持的不错
You have lasted well.
到这天Victor就已经死了
With Victor it was all over by now.
我注意到了这点
I have noticed this,
越是成熟冷静 坚持的越久
the more mature coolies seems to last longer.
请给我水 给我水喝
Water please. Could I have some water?
哦 最后的口渴
Oh, the final thirst.
你快要完了
You're near the end.
请帮帮我 尽你所能帮帮我
Please help me, help me if you can.
我可以替你隐瞒你的动机
I could champion your cause.
我的动机?
My cause?
你的工作
Your work.
它应该广为宣传
It deserves to be trumpeted.
我可以为你效劳
I could be of service.
我很怀疑
I doubt it.
多亏了你
Thanks to you
给我名誉带来了不可弥补的损害
the damage done to my reputation is irreparable.
你是说Victor Savage
You mean Victor Savage,
你的表弟
your cousin,
我都已经忘了
I had forgotten that.
你也被牵涉进来了么?
Did you, were you involved?
我有点不确定了
I couldn't be sure.
大侦探也有不清楚的时候
The great detective couldn't be sure.
就算你知道Savage是怎么死的 也没有关系
Well it doesn't matter to me if you know how Savage died.
你是不会坐在证人席上了
I don't see you in the witness box,
只可能是躺在另外一种盒子里
quite another sort of box.
就在他吸鸦片吸得不省人事的时候
I put an infected mosquito to his neck
我在他的脖子上放了一只受感染的蚊子
while he was in an opiate stupor.
就是这样
There.
但是你
But you,
你又是怎么被传染的?
how did you come to contract it?
你那个来找我的同伴
That fellow who came for me
告诉我说你是在Rotherhithe被传染的
told me you thought you caught it in Rotherhithe.
我只能这么认为
Oh, I can only account for it, so.
好好回想一下
Cast your mind back.
-痉挛? -是的
-Cramps? -Oh, yes.
-帮帮我 -我会的
-Help me. -I will.
疼痛
The pain.
死之前总是
Yes, the coolies used to do some squealing
伴随着哀号
before the end.
好吧
Well now.
在几天前 你还没有发病的时候
A few days before your symptoms began
你是不是收到过什么邮件
did you receive anything by post?
我想不起来了
I can't think.
一个包裹?
A parcel?
你收到了
You did.
是的 一些烟草的样品
Yes, samples of tobacco.
没错
That's right.
你没有注意那个盒子的结构么?
Did you notice the construction of the box?
在烟草下面
Under the tobacco,
有两根小钉子伸了出来
two small tacks stuck out.
你没有看到么?
You didn't see them?
是它传染了热病么?
They were infected?
你这傻瓜
You fool.
你找我的茬 现在你玩完了
You would tangle with me and now you are finished.
那个盒子
The box.
现在在哪?
Where is it?
在哪?
把煤气灯拧亮点
Turn up the gas.
把煤气灯拧亮点?
Turn up the gas?
影子越来越长了 是么?
The shadows begin to lengthen, do they?
好的 我来拧亮点
Yes, I'll do that.
我更喜欢在亮一点的灯光下看着你死去
I prefer to see you die in the light.
在这里
There it is,
你最后的一小点证据
your last shred of evidence.
好了
Well, well,
还有什么可以效劳的么 我的朋友
is there any other little service I can do you my friend?
火柴 香烟会很棒
A match and a cigarette would be most welcome.
三天不吃不喝是一回事
Three days without food and water is one thing,
但是抽不上烟 就太痛苦了
but to be without tobacco I have found most irksome.
探长 进来吧
Come in Inspector.
以拧亮煤气灯为信号
By turning up the gas,
Smith亲自发出了我们的信号
Smith was good enough to give our signal himself.
他坦白谋杀了Victor Savage
This is the self-confessed murderer of Victor Savage.
你可以信口开河 福尔摩斯
You may lie as you like Holmes.
但你证明不了你精神错乱的猜想
You have no corroboration for you insane suspicions.
华生 他身后有一个盒子
Watson, he has a box behind his back.
小心点拿着
Treat it very gingerly
千万别打开
and don't open it.
去死吧
Damn you.
-阻止他 -你去死吧
-Stop him. -Damn you.
扮演一个角色最成功的办法
The best way of acting a part successfully
就是成为这个角色
is to be it.
要凡士林做什么?
What's the vaseline for?
涂抹在额头
For the forehead.
眼睛里滴些颠茄酊
Belladonna in the eyes.
蜂蜡
Bee's wax.
抹在嘴唇周围
Incrustation around the lips.
为什么你不让我靠近你呢
Why wouldn't you let me near you,
事实上你并没有被感染
when in truth there was no infection?
你以为我看不起你的医道么?
Do you imagine that I have no respect for your medical talents?
距离6英尺
At six feet
我可以瞒过你
I could deceive you.
但要是更近些
But any closer,
你就会做出机敏的判断了
with your astute judgment,
不 不 不
no, no, no, no.
最重要的是
No it was essential,
你和Hudson太太要相信我快死了
that you and Mrs. Hudson believed me to be at death's door
不然Smith就像老鼠一样会有所察觉
otherwise Smith would have smelt a rat.
老鼠
Rats,
蜂蜡
bee's wax,
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
你是全伦敦最糟糕的房客了
you are the very worst tenant in London.
Georgie说他要来保卫庄园
Georgie says he's going to guard the house.
他们都是好孩子 Savage夫人
Oh they're fine children, Mrs. Savage.
就像是小天使
They're little angels.
这么多年来我们都是称为Savage家族
For years we're known as little savages.
谢谢你 华生医生
Thank you, Dr. Watson,
让我们回到家
for letting us keep our home.
谢谢你 亲爱的
Thank you my dear.
我很想接受这份荣誉
I'd like to take the credit
但那属于福尔摩斯先生
but it belongs to Mr. Holmes.
我们很感激您 先生
We are very grateful to you, sir.
是我的荣幸 Savage小姐
My privilege, Miss. Savage.
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.com==- 欢迎加入
welcome to www.1000fr.com